netneutrality.com 2017-06-07

# Privacy Policy - Battle For The Net

## **Privacy Policy**

[Fight for the Future](https://www.fightforthefuture.org/) is committed to protecting your privacy. If you sign onto one of our various mailing lists, petitions, or use our contact tools, we retain the information you provided to primarily manage our mailing lists, and secondarily to transmit only the information that is required to service providers and public officials when required to submit your communications with them. 

We do not sell our email list. We do not share or distribute your contact information unless specifically stated so. 

For petitions, open letters, or similar public communications that you've signed or completed, we treat your name, city, state, and comments as public information. We will not make your street address publicly available, but we may transmit it to public officials as part of a petition or open letter. 

We may have joint campaigns with cooperating organizations and in those cases will explicitly state that we are doing so. In those cases, if your information will be shared with another organization in order to facilitate email delivery, list management, and other stated purposes, we will explicitly make notice on any campaign or website that this organization owns before you submit any of your information. If you are submitting your information to one of these campaigns or websites, you are opting into the sharing of your information for the stated purposes and will be treated as so. We will only share information which you submit at the time of notice and will not share any person's information obtained from other past or future campaigns, knowingly or on purpose. 

We sometimes carry out our business or operate our website using third party tools. Information may be shared with the operators of those tools in connection with our use of those tools to operate our website. 

**Date changed:** 10/14/2014 

[Demand Progress/Demand Progress Action](https://demandprogress.org/) takes your privacy very seriously. We do not share your email address or other personal information with unauthorized entities without your permission. 

We use the information we collect to inform you of news that relates to Demand Progress, and to deliver petition signatures, emails/letters, and similar communications to designated targets. 

For petitions, emails/letters, or similar public communications that you’ve signed or completed, we treat your name, city, state, and comments as public information. We will not make your street or email address address publicly available, but we may transmit it to public officials/petition targets as part of a petition or open letter. (For instance, this information must be included to enable delivery of emails to members of Congress.) Demand Progress may also use cookies from third parties such as Google Adwords to served ads based on usage of this site. 

DP (our 527 arm) and DPA (our 501(c)4 arm) have a resource sharing agreement that enables each to contact activists whose contact information was gathered by the other. DP/DPA also owns and administers the WatchDog.net site. And as of the summer of 2013, DP/DPA owns and administers Rootstrikers.org. DP/DPA may contact subscribers to the Watchdog.net and Rootstrikers.org sublists. You may unsubscribe from email alerts from any or all of DP/DPA, Rootstrikers.org, or Watchdog.net at any time. 

If you enter your information as part of a clearly-labeled "joint action" with another organization, we may share your name, email, and other information you have entered with the partner organization(s) for that particular action. 

If you have any questions about our privacy policy, don’t hesitate to contact us. 

[Free Press and the Free Press Action Fund](http://freepress.net/) are committed to protecting the privacy of visitors to our website, as well as that of our members and activists. In fact, we support enhanced protections for everyone’s electronic and Internet privacy.  
In this policy, “Free Press” refers to both Free Press and Free Press Action Fund staff, board members, cooperating attorneys, interns, volunteers and consultants. 

In general, Free Press and our software partners treat your contact information as private and confidential. Free Press will not give, sell, rent, exchange or otherwise share your information with anyone else without your prior consent except as compelled by law (see below). 

We will notify users of updates to this policy by noting the date of new changes directly below this statement.

This policy was last amended on June 5, 2014. 

Policy effective May 1, 2003. 

**Website Policies**

Free Press and third-party vendor servers may record the IP address of your computer; the browser software you use and your operating system; the date and time you access our site; and the Internet address of the website from which you linked to our site. 

We use this information to measure the number of visitors to different sections of the site, to diagnose and correct system errors and to improve the site. We do not connect this information to your name or identity, and we do not retain this information permanently. 

Information that is not provided with the express intent of subscription, ordering, membership or donation will not be captured for use in other communications unless otherwise noted. We (and our vendors) restrict the use of “cookies” on this site primarily to convenience features such as auto login, surveys and polls. We typically delete these cookies as soon as is reasonably possible. We’re committed to respecting your desire to opt out of online-tracking schemes, and therefore **we include no third-party tracking buttons or beacons on our sites.**

**External Links**

Free Press has not reviewed all of the sites linked to this site and is not responsible for the privacy practices or the content of any off-site pages or any other sites linked to this site, whether or not they are affiliated with Free Press or the Free Press Action Fund. Such linked sites are for your convenience only and you access them at your own risk. Free Press makes no representations or warranties as to the accuracy or functioning of any such link. That another website is linked to our site does not constitute endorsement from Free Press or the Free Press Action Fund of the owner of the other site, the content of its site or its products or services. 

**Electronic Mailing List Policies**

Free Press offers several electronic mailing lists. If you choose to subscribe to any of these lists, we may ask for personal information such as your name, ZIP code and email address. We use this information solely to manage our lists (for example, we may use your ZIP code for a targeted mailing on an issue affecting your area). **We do not sell, rent or share any information from our electronic mailing lists.**

There are a number of ways to subscribe to Free Press’ electronic mailing lists, including submitting a form on our website, opting in when you engage in online or offline activism, or mailing or completing a sign-up form from a paper petition, brochure or flier. When you subscribe, you will typically receive a confirmation message welcoming you. 

You may unsubscribe from any of our lists at any time. If you wish to update your information, delete or otherwise make changes to your relationship with us, or remove yourself entirely from our list(s), [click here.](http://act2.freepress.net/unsubscribe/unsubscribe_freepress/)

Lists Free Press maintains for electronic mailings are exclusively “opt-in” lists. We do not purchase information from third-party sources or gather personal data from the Web (known as spidering) for inclusion in our email lists. 

**Online Activism**

Our website offers many ways to engage in online activism. Many of these tools are hosted and administered by a third party (currently ActionKit). When you provide personal information by signing a petition or engaging in other actions, that personal information may be stored on our server(s) and/or ActionKit’s server(s). If you choose to join a mailing list or become a member at the same time that you participate in an online action, your relevant information will be kept and used for those other purposes.

We may deliver petitions and surveys you’ve completed to the president, federal and state legislators, agencies like the Federal Communications Commission, other elected and appointed officials, or other entities such as companies whose policies we seek to change. We ask for your address so we can deliver your message to the appropriate legislative offices, and may include information such as your name, town or city and state in these deliveries. 

ActionKit strictly adheres to policies preventing unauthorized access to your personal information and will not make such information available to anyone outside of Free Press or ActionKit (unless legally compelled to do so). 

**Financial Support**

Free Press and the Free Press Action Fund are committed to maintaining the trust and security of all financial supporters. We collect personal information including the email and mailing addresses that members and donors provide. We might use this information for online and print mailings to keep you informed about our programs and occasionally to ask for additional financial support. You may opt out of these communications at any time. 

To opt out of email communication, [click here.](http://act2.freepress.net/unsubscribe/unsubscribe_freepress/)

To opt out of print mailings, please call us at 413-585-1533 or [email Rachel Courtney](mailto:rcourtney@freepress.net). 

On occasion, Free Press or the Free Press Action Fund sends messages on behalf of other reputable organizations when we believe such messages may be of value to our members and supporters. Our ability to send you these messages on behalf of other entities helps us build our membership base and further the movement for your rights to connect and communicate. If you do not wish to receive such messages from our allied or aligned organizations, please call us at 413-585-1533 or [email Rachel Courtney](mailto:rcourtney@freepress.net). Free Press is not responsible for the privacy practices or the content produced or provided by any of these other entities. 

All financial data is collected via a secure Web connection, and is stored or transmitted using appropriate security measures at all times. 

**Online and Phone Orders for Materials**

Information provided to us in the course of placing an order for educational materials, activist toolkits, promotional materials or other materials offered by Free Press (whether or not the materials are offered at a cost) may be retained for use in future communications, such as membership drives, or when we unveil similar offerings we believe may be of interest to you. This information will not be given, sold, rented, shared or otherwise provided to anyone else without your prior consent (except when compelled by law — see below). 

All financial data is collected via a secure Web connection, and is stored or transmitted using appropriate security measures at all times. 

**Compelled Disclosure**

If we are required by law to disclose any information that you have provided us, we will attempt to give you notice (unless we are prohibited from doing so) that a request for your information has been made, in order to give you an opportunity to object. We will attempt to provide this notice by email, if you have given us an email address, or by postal mail if you have entered a postal address. If you do not challenge the disclosure request, we may be legally required to turn over your information. In addition, we may independently object to any disclosures we believe to be improper. 

**Questions?**

If you would like additional information about our privacy practices and/or our policies, please contact info(AT)freepress.net. 

**Copyright Policies**

All original text, images and other materials hosted on freepress.net servers are copyright 2009–2014 Free Press, unless otherwise noted (e.g., news articles and licensed photos). 

We encourage reproduction and distribution of original materials on this site for educational and personal use. All Free Press-created content on this site (unless otherwise noted) is available to you under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike license. 

In short, this license allows you to copy, distribute, display or make derivative works provided that you a) credit Free Press, b) do not use it for commercial purposes and c) release any derivative works under this same license. 

**Copyright-Infringement Notification**

If you have a copyright complaint, please follow the procedures set forth in the Digital Millennium Copyright Act. Our agent for notice is Kimberly Longey, chief operating officer. She may be reached by phone at 413.585.1533, by fax at 413.585.8904 or by email at copyright@freepress.net. Please direct your written correspondence to her at: 

Free Press  
40 Main St., Suite 301  
Florence, MA 01062  

We take your privacy seriously. We understand that your personal information is just that: yours. We will never give it to any entity or organization without your consent, and we sure as hell won’t sell it to turn a profit. 

For petitions, open letters, or similar public communications that you’ve signed or completed, we treat your name, city, state, and comments as public information. We will not make your street address publicly available, but we may transmit this information to members of Congress, the President, or other public figures on your behalf. If you complete a phone call using our call tool, we will not make that publicly available, either. Your phone number may be shared with your member of Congress, the President, or other public figures during your call. 

By completing an action (like signing a petition or completing a phone call), you’re opting in to receive 18MR.org updates by email. If you would like to unsubscribe from our email list, you may do so at any time. (Take a look at the footer of any email you’ve received from us for your personalized link.) 

Your use of this site is consent to gather information about your visit. We track traffic and may also log information that helps us improve our website and tools. Most data will be collected in aggregate, such as through Google Analytics. 

Our action platform, [Action Network](https://actionnetwork.org/), uses cookies to track your login to their system. You can read [their complete privacy policy here](https://actionnetwork.org/privacy).

You can block the use of these and other trackers using [the EFF’s Privacy Badger plugin](https://www.eff.org/privacybadger). We won’t be mad. (But you might need to disable it occasionally to fully load features on our site.)

If you have any questions about this privacy policy or our treatment of your personal data, [please drop us a line](mailto:info@18millionrising.org).

## Back to Battle for the Net
